Guide to the Allegheny Observatory Records, 1850-1977 UA.5.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Photographs, 1886-1922; XVI.
  - Photographic Negatives, 1.
    - Personal Photography of Frank C. Jordan
      - Family, Friends
        - MacIvor and Jordan family and Dr. Martin (June 1914) (Box 8, Folder 19)
        - The Armstrong house (July 4, 1914) (Box 8, Folder 20)
        - Krom House (July 4, 1914) (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - The Krom family (July 4, 1914) (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - The whole family (April 25, 1915) (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Andrew as Uncle Sam (May 30, 1915) (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Harriet and F.C. Jordan (November 25, 1915) (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Thanksgiving, Harriet and F.C. Jordan, Andrew, Will and Sadie (1915) (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Group at Aunt Mary Reed's (July 19, 1916) (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - John William with dog (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Interior at Cheswick (February 8, 1917) (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - John William (1918) (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - John William at desk (April 21, 1918) (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Dr. F. C. Jordan in a silk hat (April 21, 1918) (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Group at Beaver (July 19, 1918) (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Foundations of house at Beaver (Box 9, Folder 14)
        - Rosecroft, S.E. front (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - House at Beaver from southwest (July 22, 1918) (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Andrew (July 22, 1918) (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - Rosecroft (Box 9, Folder 18)
        - Fireplace at Rosecroft (Box 9, Folder 19)
        - Family group on porch, Rosecroft, Beaver, PA (Box 9, Folder 20)
        - Flower garden at Beaver (Box 9, Folder 21)
        - Group working in flowers at Beaver, PA. (July 25, 1918) (Box 9, Folder 22)
        - Garage at Beaver, PA. (July 25, 1918) (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Family group on rocks at Beaver, PA. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - M.E. Church, Children's Day (June 11, 19_) (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Watson Church, Harvest House decorations (November 2, 1919) (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Watson church, Harvest Home decorations (November 2, 1919) (Box 10, Folder 5)
        - John William at telescope (November 14, 1919) (Box 10, Folder 6)
        - Jean, Observatory steps (January 1, 1921) (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - F.C. Jordan. (February 12, 1921) (Box 10, Folder 8)
        - "Sandy" and Catherine Lamb in living room, Cheswick (March 12, 1921) (Box 10, Folder 9)
        - "Sandy" Lamb (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Views in Ohio
        - Snow scene, 49 Riverview (March 4, 1922) (Box 10, Folder 11)
        - Ohio Company's office, Washington St. (F.C. Jordan, photographer: December 29, 1898) (Box 10, Folder 12)
        - Mound Cemetery, from north, Charlie Carothers on the steps (F.C. Jordan, photographer: December 28, 1898) (Box 10, Folder 13)
        - Mound Cemetery (Box 10, Folder 14)
        - University Hall, Ohio State University (August 22, 1899) (Box 10, Folder 15)
        - Ohio State University grounds (August 22, 1899) (Box 10, Folder 16)
        - Orton Hall and Biology Lab, Ohio State University (August 22, 1899) (Box 10, Folder 17)
        - Deaf and Dumb Asylum, Columbus, Ohio (August 23, 1899) (Box 10, Folder 18)
        - Death Cell, Ohio State Penitentiary (Box 10, Folder 19)
        - Picnic group at Fredericktown, Ohio (May 30, 1909) (Box 10, Folder 20)
        - Children fishing, Fredericktown, Ohio (1909) (Box 10, Folder 21)
        - Indian carvings, Smith's Ferry, Ohio (1909) (Box 10, Folder 22)
        - Children, East Liverpool, Ohio (1909) (Box 10, Folder 23)
        - Family group on rocks, Smith's Ferry, Ohio (1909) (Box 11, Folder 1)
        - House and family at East Liverpool, Ohio (1909) (Box 11, Folder 2)
        - Old Caywood house, Wheeler house (July 19, 1916) (Box 11, Folder 3)
        - Caywood house, Washington County, Ohio. (Box 11, Folder 4)
        - Caywood house, Hills P.O. (Box 11, Folder 5)
        - Marietta and river from Harmer Hill, Ohio (Box 11, Folder 6)
        - Mill at Beverly, Ohio (Box 11, Folder 7)
        - House 618, Second St., Marietta, Ohio (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Views in Wisconsin
        - Reflector dome and Lake Geneva, Yerkes Observatory (Box 11, Folder 9)
        - Lake Geneva, from top of Yerkes Observatory, looking east (Box 11, Folder 10)
        - Yerkes Observatory (Box 11, Folder 11)
        - 2 foot reflector, Yerkes Observatory. (Box 11, Folder 12)
        - Yerkes group (1907) (Box 11, Folder 13)
        - Yerkes group (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Views in Colorado
        - Chamberlin Observatory (June 8, 1918) (Box 11, Folder 15-17)
        - Mountains from Chamberlin Observatory (June 8, 1918) (Box 11, Folder 18)
        - Clock at Knob Hill Station, Colorado Springs (Box 11, Folder 19)
        - Cooke camera at Knob Hill, Colorado Springs (Box 11, Folder 20)
        - Range south of Pike's Peak, from Knob Hill (Box 11, Folder 21)
        - Pike's Peak and range from Knob Hill (June 9, 1918) (Box 12, Folder 1)
        - Pike's Peak and range (June 9, 1918) (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
        - Train on Midland Road, base of Pike's Peak (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Engine, Pike's Peak Cog Road (Box 12, Folder 5)
        - Pike's Peak Cog Road, near half-way house (Box 12, Folder 6)
        - Looking down along Pike's Peak Cog Road (Box 12, Folder 7)
        - Pike's Peak Cog Road, ascending curve (Box 12, Folder 8)
        - Manitou and front range, Pike's Peak region (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - Geology class at Manitou ready to go up to Lake Moraine (Box 12, Folder 10)
        - Bald Mountain from Lake Moraine (Box 12, Folder 11)
        - Williams Canyon, Manitou, Colorado (Box 12, Folder 12)
        - Rocks in Williams Canyon. (Box 12, Folder 13)
        - Amphitheater, Williams Canyon, Manitou, Colorado (Box 12, Folder 14)
        - Pavilion at Manitou, Soda Springs. (Box 12, Folder 15)
        - Geology class at Seven Falls, South Cheyenne Canyon (Box 12, Folder 16)
        - View from top of Seven Falls, Cheyenne Canyon (Box 12, Folder 17)
        - Father and Uncle Spence at top of Seven Falls (Box 12, Folder 18)
        - South Cheyenne Canyon, Colorado Springs (Box 12, Folder 19)
        - Family group, South Cheyenne canyon (Box 12, Folder 20)
        - Ice in South Cheyenne Canyon (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - "Needless," North Cheyenne Canyon (Box 13, Folder 2)
        - Cheyenne Mountain. (June 9, 1918) (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - Cheyenne Mountain, from the west (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - Cheyenne Mountain, from Canyon Park (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - Valley west of Cheyenne Mountain, Colorado Springs (Box 13, Folder 6)
        - Plains, Colorado Springs, east from Knob Hill (Box 13, Folder 7)
        - Plains south of Colorado Springs, Cheyenne Canyon (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - Family group at cabin, St. Peter's Dome, Colorado Springs (Box 13, Folder 9)
        - St. Peter's Dome, Colorado Springs (Box 13, Folder 10)
        - Geology class, Red Rock Canyon, Colorado Springs (Box 13, Folder 11)
        - Geology class in Garden of the Gods (Box 13, Folder 12)
        - Gateway, Garden of the Gods (Box 13, Folder 13)
        - Rocks in Garden of the Gods (Box 13, Folder 14)
        - Balanced Rock, Garden of the Gods (Box 13, Folder 15)
        - Rocks in Garden of the Gods (Seal and Bear) (Box 13, Folder 16)
        - Group in Garden of the Gods, at Siamese Twins (Box 13, Folder 17)
        - Profile Rock, Garden of the Gods (Box 13, Folder 18)
        - Rocks in Monument Park, Colorado (Box 13, Folder 19)
        - "Quaker Wedding," Monument Park, Colorado (Box 13, Folder 20)
        - Cox house and group, Colorado Springs (Box 13, Folder 21)
        - High School, Colorado Springs (Box 13, Folder 22)
        - On Tennessee Pass, near Leadville, Colorado (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Views in the West
        - Along the Union Pacific (March 1900) (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - Sagebrush plains, Wyoming or Idaho (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - Sacramento State House (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - Ground, State House, Sacramento (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Various Views
        - Oil field, Moore's Junction (F.C. Jordan, photographer: December 30, 1898) (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - Houses at toll gate, 9 miles from government camp (6 A.M. September 2, 1900) (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - Multiple lightning flash (F.C. Jordan photographer: August 27, 1904) (Box 14, Folder 8)
        - 208 Club (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - Mr. Barnhard's observatory (May 4, 1907) (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Bi-plane (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Red Cross nurse at "Flu" hospital (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - Indian Mound at Oakmont, beginning of operations (October 4, 1895) (Box 14, Folder 13)
        - Indian Mound Oakmont (October 4, 1895) (Box 14, Folder 14)
        - Indian Mound Oakmont, from west (October 4, 1895) (Box 14, Folder 15)
        - View toward Schoenberger Iron Works in Strip District, from base of P. Ft. W. C. Ry. Bridge (c. 1900) (Box 14, Folder 16)
        - Pittsburgh fireworks (July 4, 1901) (Box 14, Folder 17)
        - Phipps Conservatory, North Side (Box 14, Folder 18)
        - 208 Club (Box 14, Folder 19)
        - Perry High School, from Perrysville Ave. (Box 15, Folder 15)
        - Looking west above Perrysville Ave., up plank road. (Box 15, Folder 2)
        - Backyard telescope (Box 15, Folder 3)
        - Residence of Major Speer, Oakmont, Pa., October 4, 1895 (Box 15, Folder 4)
        - Parlour, Residence, JEK (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
        - Austin Bluffs, Colorado Springs (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - Thaw Refracter Negatives, March 9, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Photographic Prints, 2.
    - Dr. Brashear (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
    - Dr. Brashear's Wife (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Dr. Brashear's Mother (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Dr. Brashear with Alexander Graham Bell and Others (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Brashear Memorial Subscription Book Signing (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny Observatory (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
    - First Photograph of the Nebula in Orion (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Photograph of the Nebula in Orion (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - William Thaw (negative available) (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Allegheny Observatory Prints (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Instruments (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Individuals (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Observations (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Various Views (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - New Material Added, 2013
      - 30 inch Keeler Telescope (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
      - Thaw Telescope (No. 3123A) (Box 18, Folder 3)
        Photographs of the Thaw Telescope taken by George Plaetvich. Date Unknown.
      - Telescope Components, March, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 4)
        Photographs taken by George Vargo, March 1973.
      - Photograph used in Publication, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 5)
        Photograph of Researchers in front of image tubes display, 1968 (?) L-R: Joost H. Kiewiet de Jonge, Wallace R. Beardsley, and J.R. Hansen.
      - Basement - Library Photographs (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
      - Gaertner Scientific - M1233 Comparator (A & B) (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Grant - Measuring Machines (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Grant Data System (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Riddell Scientific Instrument - Williams Bay, Wis. (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Small Brashear Measuring Engine (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Iron Spectrum - Vatican Atlas (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Spectrum Enlargements (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Thaw Dome, August 1972 (Box 18, Folder 15)
        Photographs of the Thaw Dome with Scaffolding. Taken August 1972.
- Student Records, 1960-1977; XVII.
  Access Restrictions
  Access restricted without signed confidentiality agreement.
  - Barrick, John (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Breakiron, Lee (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Caglayan, Aybars (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Engel, Thomas (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Fluharty, John R. (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Gatewood, George (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Gault, Andrew (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Gbur, Nicholas J. (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Giannini, Judith (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Grimble, Ralph E. (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Hayes, James C. (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Jett, James Eric (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Jones, George W. (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Kamper, Karl W. (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Kimmel, Frank W. (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - King, Merle (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - Kipp, Steven (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Kirshnawamy, Parvalthi (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Lavie, Aharon (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Lippert, Kenneth B. (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - Mechler, Gary (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Mesrobian, William S. (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Mousseau, Robert (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Nelson, Robert M. (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Olejniczak, Paul J. (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Peters, Lawrence E. Jr. (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Parise, Ronald Anthony (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Parks, Allen D. (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Russel, Jane (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Schwab, Harry L. (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Sprinkle, Thomas G. (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Stein, John William (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Tepper, Lawrence J. (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Trybula, Walter (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Urbaniak, John J. (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Vaerewyck, Eugene G. (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Worek, Thaddeus (Box 79, Folder 17)
  - Zajdel, Theodore T. J. (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Ziska, Eugene R. (Box 79, Folder 19)